When others fly out, heroes fly in.
Planes: Fire & Rescue is a animation, comedy,
adventure film directed by Bobs Gannaway.
When world-famous air racer Dusty learns that his engine is damaged and he may never race
again, he must shift gears and is launched into the world of aerial firefighting.
Dusty joins forces with veteran fire and rescue helicopter Blade Ranger and his
team, a bunch of all-terrain vehicles known as The Smokejumpers.
Together, the fearless team battles a massive wildfire, and
Dusty learns what it takes to become a true hero.
Blade Ranger (voice), played by Ed Harris.
Dusty Crophopper (voice), played by Dane Cook.
Dipper (voice), played by Julie Bowen.
Maru (voice), played by Curtis Armstrong.
Cad (voice), played by John Michael Higgins.
Mayday (voice), played by Hal Holbrook.
Planes 2: Fire & Rescue is a 2014 American animated comedy-adventure film
produced by Disneytoon Studios and released by Walt Disney Pictures.
Directed by Bobs Gannaway, written by Gannaway and Jeffrey M.
Howard, and produced by Ferrell Barron, it is a sequel to Planes
(2013), itself a spin-off of Pixar's Cars franchise.
Dane Cook, Stacy Keach, Brad Garrett, Teri Hatcher, Danny Mann, and Cedric the Entertainer reprised their roles with new additions
to the cast including Hal Holbrook, Julie Bowen, Ed Harris, Regina King, Wes Studi, Patrick Warburton, and Dale Dye.
In the film, Dusty Crophopper (Cook) is assigned to become a wildland firefighting plane in
Piston Peak National Park after he learns that his engine's gearbox is damaged.
Production began for six months after the start of the previous film.
Gannaway intended to give each film its own different genre,
Planes: Fire & Rescue being an "action-disaster film".
The filmmakers researched the world of air-attack teams and smokejumpers by working with the California Department of Forestry and
Fire Protection (CALFire), and sent a crew to the US Forest Service's annual training exercises for smokejumpers.
Mark Mancina composed the musical score again, while Prana Studios returned to
provided work on visual effects, animation and compositing.
Planes: Fire & Rescue premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Los Angeles on July 15, 2014, and was
theatrically released on July 18, 2014, in Disney Digital 3D, RealD 3D and D-BOX formats.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, with many calling it an improvement over its
predecessor, and grossed $147 million worldwide on a $50 million budget.
The film explores themes of national park, sequel,
anthropomorphism, firefighter, smoke jumpers.
The tone is lighthearted.